<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Software Testing Blog - thebugger.io</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Software Testing Blog - thebugger.io</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 04 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Running Cypress Test Script on multiple URLs</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/post11/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/post11/</guid>
      <description>Today we will create Cypress Testing Script that will be performed on multiple URLs. Let&amp;rsquo;s start! First we need to create Environment Variables in cypress.json file. Those variables will store our URLs but also usernames and passwords, needed in login process:
{ &amp;#34;ignoreTestFiles&amp;#34;: &amp;#34;*/examples/&amp;#34;, &amp;#34;viewportHeight&amp;#34;: 1080, &amp;#34;viewportWidth&amp;#34;: 1920, &amp;#34;pageLoadTimeout&amp;#34;: 20000, &amp;#34;defaultCommandTimeout&amp;#34;: 8000, &amp;#34;retries&amp;#34;: 3, &amp;#34;env&amp;#34;: { &amp;#34;URL1.be&amp;#34;: { &amp;#34;url&amp;#34;: &amp;#34;https://url1.be&amp;#34;, &amp;#34;username&amp;#34;: &amp;#34;uname&amp;#34;, &amp;#34;password&amp;#34;: &amp;#34;pword&amp;#34; }, &amp;#34;URL1.ch&amp;#34;: { &amp;#34;url&amp;#34;: &amp;#34;https://url1.ch&amp;#34;, &amp;#34;username&amp;#34;: &amp;#34;uname&amp;#34;, &amp;#34;password&amp;#34;: &amp;#34;pword&amp;#34; }, &amp;#34;URL1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Https but still not secure?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/post10/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/post10/</guid>
      <description>Does your URL start with HTTPS but still is marked as not secure? Let&amp;rsquo;s take a closer look at it. HTTPS stands for “Hypertext Transfer Protocol Secure”. It allows for the secure flow of information between a server and client. It may happen that although your URL starts with HTTPS and there is nothing wrong with your SSL certificate, web browsers will indicate that connection to your site is not secure:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Page Objects in Cypress - introduction</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/post9/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/post9/</guid>
      <description>In this short article we are going to learn how to use Page Objects in Cypress. Page Objects make end-to-end tests readable and easy to maintain. Among others there are three main benefits of using them:
 Keeping all page element selectors in one place Possibility to use Page Objects in multiple tests Standardizing how tests interact with the page  To simplyfy, we can say, that Page Object encapsulates the mechanics in GUI and allows us to find and manipulate page elements without digging around in the HTML.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>API testing with Cypress - quick overview</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/post8/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/post8/</guid>
      <description>This article will be an introduction to Cypress API testing. Cypress supports operations like GET, POST, PUT, DELETE, PATCH, HEAD and many more. This quick overview will be focused on GET, POST and DELETE.
Without further ado, let&amp;rsquo;s create our first API test with Cypress:
describe(&amp;#39;First GET Request Test&amp;#39;, () =&amp;gt; { it(&amp;#34;Checking Status Code for our URL&amp;#34;, () =&amp;gt; { cy.request(&amp;#34;https://oururl.com/somesubpage&amp;#34;).as(&amp;#39;res&amp;#39;) .its(&amp;#39;status&amp;#39;) .should(&amp;#39;equal&amp;#39;, 200); cy.get(&amp;#39;@res&amp;#39;) .its(&amp;#39;headers&amp;#39;) .its(&amp;#39;content-type&amp;#39;) .should(&amp;#39;include&amp;#39;, &amp;#39;application/json; charset=utf-8&amp;#39;); }); }); Here, using an inbuilt assertion library (Chai), we made a basic check.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Is multi-tab testing supported by Cypress?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/post7/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/post7/</guid>
      <description>In the previous post I mentioned that Cypress does not support multi-tab testing. But is there anything we can do in some cases? Let&amp;rsquo;s find out. Let&amp;rsquo;s say that we need to perform an end to end test of our blog. We want to be sure that included github link is working properly. First we need to visit our blog:
cy.visit(&amp;lsquo;https://thebugger.io/&#39;);
Then, in order to check if github link is working, we need to click it and see if the outcome of this action is correct.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cypress - advantages and disadvantages</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/post6/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/post6/</guid>
      <description>To convince anyone how beneficial automated software testing is, is not needed. Automated software testing is much faster than manual testing and what is most important - it is repeatable. We need to rememberr however, that automated testing should be a great supplement and support for manual testing - not a replacement. The test script works only as it was programmed and does a great job. However, nothing can replace the skilled eye of an experienced tester.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>JavaScriptExecutor in Selenium - introduction</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/post5/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/post5/</guid>
      <description>It turns that Crayfish might be much smarter than we have ever imagined. So clever, they can grow new brain cells from their own blood. However, this article will be about JavascriptExecutor in Selenium. You may come across situations where Selenium WebDriver alone will not be able to perform certain operations or interact with some web elements, like unexpected pop-ups. In that case, JavascriptExecutor comes in handy. Let’s have a closer look on that topic.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Waits in Selenium - quick overview</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/post4/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/post4/</guid>
      <description>Let&amp;rsquo;s have a closer look at Implicit and Explicit Wait in Selenium. The wait commands play essential role when it comes to automated testing. They help to avoid issues that may occur due to variation in time lag. When the webpage loads in the browser, its elements may load at different time intervals. This may lead to the situation in which our automated test will look for an element that is not yet loaded and an exception will be thrown - ElementNotVisibleException.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The differences between TDD and BDD</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/post3/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/post3/</guid>
      <description>In this blog post we are going to discover the main differences between two testing-related concepts - Test Driven Development and Behavior Driven Development. TDD and BDD are two widely used software development techniques in which automated testing plays a central role. Today we are going to explore the differences.
Let&amp;rsquo;s start with Test Driven Development. Typically, in this technique, we write tests for a certain piece of functionality before writing the production code.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Selenium - advantages and disadvantages</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/post2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/post2/</guid>
      <description>Creating and adding your project to GitHub can let you build your portfolio, share your work and collaborate with others. Let&amp;rsquo;s start! In case you don&amp;rsquo;t have Git installed yet, check this article on how to set it up.
If you already have Git installed, create a new repository on GitHub, open Terminal and navigate into the directory where your source code (project) is located and initialize the local directory as a Git repository using:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to add a project to GitHub using command line</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/post1/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/post1/</guid>
      <description>Creating and adding your project to GitHub can let you build your portfolio, share your work and collaborate with others. Let&amp;rsquo;s start! In case you don&amp;rsquo;t have Git installed yet, check this article on how to set it up.
If you already have Git installed, create a new repository on GitHub, open Terminal and navigate into the directory where your source code (project) is located and initialize the local directory as a Git repository using:</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
