<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Software Testing Blog - thebugger.io</title>
    <link>https://jjaworski93.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Software Testing Blog - thebugger.io</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 03 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://jjaworski93.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Mocking HTTP calls with Cypress</title>
      <link>https://jjaworski93.github.io/post/post23/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jjaworski93.github.io/post/post23/</guid>
      <description>Mocking HTTP calls allows us to test the behavior of our code under various conditions and isolate it from the external services it relies on, making our tests more reliable, repeatable and efficient. Mocking a HTTP call means to simulate the behavior of a real HTTP call in a controlled environment, typically during the test process. This is done by creating a mock object that mimics the interface of the real HTTP call.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>HTTP - methods, headers, cookies, etc.</title>
      <link>https://jjaworski93.github.io/post/post22/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jjaworski93.github.io/post/post22/</guid>
      <description>An HTTP (Hypertext Transfer Protocol) request is a message sent by a client, such as a web browser or a mobile app, to a server in order to retrieve or send information. When client makes an HTTP request to a server, the server processes the request and sends an appropriate response back to the client. This response can be a web page, an image, a file, or an error message, among other things.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Token&#39;s Security testing with Cypress</title>
      <link>https://jjaworski93.github.io/post/post21/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jjaworski93.github.io/post/post21/</guid>
      <description>Cypress allows us to interact with a webpage and its underlying resources, such as cookies. We can use Cypress to check if tokens are properly stored, encrypted, expired, and invalidated, as well as other security properties such as the &amp;lsquo;httpOnly&amp;rsquo; and &amp;lsquo;secure&amp;rsquo; attributes. The following examples will be based on an banking web app. First we log in, then we use the getCookie method to check for the cookies (tokens) in the browser.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fuzz Testing with Cypress - introduction</title>
      <link>https://jjaworski93.github.io/post/post20/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jjaworski93.github.io/post/post20/</guid>
      <description>Fuzz Testing is a method of Software Testing that involves providing invalid, unexpected or random data called FUZZ into a Software System in order to discover errors, crashes and security loopholes. Could such test be performed in Cypress? The goal of Fuzz Testing is to find bugs that are difficult to discover through manual testing. Such test is often used to test the security of a system by attempting to find vulnerabilities that could be exploited by an attacker.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pseudo Website Scraper - copy function</title>
      <link>https://jjaworski93.github.io/post/post19/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jjaworski93.github.io/post/post19/</guid>
      <description>Let&amp;rsquo;s create a pseudo data scraper with copy() function and browser console. The copy() function can be used to easily fetch some data from the page. For example, let&amp;rsquo;s say that we want to fetch the list of all the team members from Our Team gallery that looks like this:
&amp;lt;img src=&amp;#34;name_familyname.jpg&amp;#34; alt=&amp;#34;Name Familyname&amp;#34; width=&amp;#34;500&amp;#34; height=&amp;#34;600&amp;#34;&amp;gt; In this case, we can use the copy() function and alt attribute:
copy($$(&amp;#39;img&amp;#39;).map(img =&amp;gt; img.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Terminal Commands - Cheatsheet</title>
      <link>https://jjaworski93.github.io/post/post18/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jjaworski93.github.io/post/post18/</guid>
      <description>Terminal - list of essential commands. With so many Terminal commands, it is difficult to remember all of them. That is why I prepared a cheatsheet list of essential Terminal commands.
Hope this article was useful.
Thanks for reading!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>JavaScript Best Practices - Cheatsheet (No. 5)</title>
      <link>https://jjaworski93.github.io/post/post17/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jjaworski93.github.io/post/post17/</guid>
      <description>JavaScript - a fifth list of the Tips and Best Practices. This is the fifth article in the JavaScript Tips &amp;amp; Best Practices series. Let&amp;rsquo;s begin.
21. Fulfilling Array with same data. There may be times when you need a very long Array with the same elements. In such situations .fill() method comes in handy:
let newArray = new Array(100).fill(1); console.log(newArray); // [1, 1, 1, 1, 1, 1, 1, 1, 1, 1, 1, 1,.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>JavaScript Best Practices - Cheatsheet (No. 4)</title>
      <link>https://jjaworski93.github.io/post/post16/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jjaworski93.github.io/post/post16/</guid>
      <description>JavaScript - a fourth list of the Tips and Best Practices. This is the fourth article in the JavaScript Tips &amp;amp; Best Practices series. Let&amp;rsquo;s get right into it.
16. Merging arrays with spread operator. The Spread Operator (three dots) has many different uses and I will definitely write a separate article about it. Basically, the Spread Operator allows us to spread out elements of an iterable object such as an Array, Set, or Map.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>JavaScript Best Practices - Cheatsheet (No. 3)</title>
      <link>https://jjaworski93.github.io/post/post15/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jjaworski93.github.io/post/post15/</guid>
      <description>JavaScript - a third list of the Tips and Best Practices. This is the third article in the JavaScript Tips &amp;amp; Best Practices series. Let&amp;rsquo;s get straight to the point.
11. Verify that given argument is a number - to verify that a given argument is a number, we could use below function:
function isNumber(n){ return !isNaN(parseFloat(n)) &amp;amp;&amp;amp; isFinite(n); } console.log(isNumeric(12345)); // true console.log(isNumeric(&amp;#39;5 &amp;#39;)); // true console.log(isNumeric(&amp;#34;-55.1 &amp;#34;)); // true console.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>JavaScript Best Practices - Cheatsheet (No. 2)</title>
      <link>https://jjaworski93.github.io/post/post14/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jjaworski93.github.io/post/post14/</guid>
      <description>JavaScript - a second list of the Tips and Best Practices. This is the second article in the JavaScript Tips &amp;amp; Best Practices series. Let&amp;rsquo;s cut straight to the chase.
6. Object Constructor - is a special function that creates and initializes an object instance of a class. The purpose of such constructor is to create a new object and set values for any existing object properties. It is considered a good practice to name constructor functions with an upper-case first letter.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>JavaScript Best Practices - Cheatsheet (No. 1)</title>
      <link>https://jjaworski93.github.io/post/post13/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jjaworski93.github.io/post/post13/</guid>
      <description>JavaScript - a list of the Tips and Best Practices. In this article, I decided to gather some of the JavaScript tips and best practices. Let&amp;rsquo;s get right into it!
1. Truthy / Falsy values - in JavaScript all values, except those listed below, are considered to be truthy:
 false 0 (but not as a string) ““ and &#39;&#39; (empty strings) null undefined NaN (Not a Number)  2. Converting string to a number with + operator.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chrome DevTools - a built-in color picker</title>
      <link>https://jjaworski93.github.io/post/post12/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jjaworski93.github.io/post/post12/</guid>
      <description>Google Chrome DevTools - a built-in color picker that you probably didn&amp;rsquo;t know existed. Chrome DevTools is a set of very useful tools built directly into the browser. Among all these tools, there is also a color picker which this post will be about. Let&amp;rsquo;s start.
First we need to open Chrome DevTools. You can do this by using keyboard shortcuts:
 Ctrl + Shift + I (Windows) Command + Option + I (Mac)  or you can just right-click somewhere on the page and then select “Inspect”:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Running Cypress Test Script on multiple URLs</title>
      <link>https://jjaworski93.github.io/post/post11/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jjaworski93.github.io/post/post11/</guid>
      <description>Today we will create Cypress Testing Script that will be performed on multiple URLs. Let&amp;rsquo;s start! First we need to create Environment Variables in cypress.json file. Those variables will store our URLs but also usernames and passwords, needed in login process:
{ &amp;#34;ignoreTestFiles&amp;#34;: &amp;#34;*/examples/&amp;#34;, &amp;#34;viewportHeight&amp;#34;: 1080, &amp;#34;viewportWidth&amp;#34;: 1920, &amp;#34;pageLoadTimeout&amp;#34;: 20000, &amp;#34;defaultCommandTimeout&amp;#34;: 8000, &amp;#34;retries&amp;#34;: 3, &amp;#34;env&amp;#34;: { &amp;#34;URL1.be&amp;#34;: { &amp;#34;url&amp;#34;: &amp;#34;https://url1.be&amp;#34;, &amp;#34;username&amp;#34;: &amp;#34;uname&amp;#34;, &amp;#34;password&amp;#34;: &amp;#34;pword&amp;#34; }, &amp;#34;URL1.ch&amp;#34;: { &amp;#34;url&amp;#34;: &amp;#34;https://url1.ch&amp;#34;, &amp;#34;username&amp;#34;: &amp;#34;uname&amp;#34;, &amp;#34;password&amp;#34;: &amp;#34;pword&amp;#34; }, &amp;#34;URL1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Https but still not secure?</title>
      <link>https://jjaworski93.github.io/post/post10/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jjaworski93.github.io/post/post10/</guid>
      <description>Does your URL start with HTTPS but still is marked as not secure? Let&amp;rsquo;s take a closer look at it. HTTP (Hypertext Transfer Protocol) is a protocol that enables communication between the client and the server. Its job is to identify, share and convert the content so that the content can be read correctly by the server. The user sends a request to the server (e.g. by entering a website address) and within a moment receives a response (displaying a given page).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Page Objects in Cypress - introduction</title>
      <link>https://jjaworski93.github.io/post/post9/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jjaworski93.github.io/post/post9/</guid>
      <description>In this short article we are going to learn how to use Page Objects in Cypress. Page Objects make end-to-end tests readable and easy to maintain. Among others there are three main benefits of using them:
 Keeping all page element selectors in one place Possibility to use Page Objects in multiple tests Standardizing how tests interact with the page  To simplyfy, we can say, that Page Object encapsulates the mechanics in GUI and allows us to find and manipulate page elements without digging around in the HTML.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>API testing with Cypress - quick overview</title>
      <link>https://jjaworski93.github.io/post/post8/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jjaworski93.github.io/post/post8/</guid>
      <description>This article will be an introduction to Cypress API testing. Cypress supports operations like GET, POST, PUT, DELETE, PATCH, HEAD and many more. This quick overview will be focused on GET, POST and DELETE.
Without further ado, let&amp;rsquo;s create our first API test with Cypress:
describe(&amp;#39;First GET Request Test&amp;#39;, () =&amp;gt; { it(&amp;#34;Checking Status Code for our URL&amp;#34;, () =&amp;gt; { cy.request(&amp;#34;https://oururl.com/somesubpage&amp;#34;).as(&amp;#39;res&amp;#39;) .its(&amp;#39;status&amp;#39;) .should(&amp;#39;equal&amp;#39;, 200); cy.get(&amp;#39;@res&amp;#39;) .its(&amp;#39;headers&amp;#39;) .its(&amp;#39;content-type&amp;#39;) .should(&amp;#39;include&amp;#39;, &amp;#39;application/json; charset=utf-8&amp;#39;); }); }); Here, using an inbuilt assertion library (Chai), we made a basic check.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Is multi-tab testing supported by Cypress?</title>
      <link>https://jjaworski93.github.io/post/post7/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jjaworski93.github.io/post/post7/</guid>
      <description>In the previous post I mentioned that Cypress does not support multi-tab testing. But is there anything we can do in some cases? Let&amp;rsquo;s find out. Let&amp;rsquo;s say that we need to perform an end to end test of our blog. We want to be sure that included github link is working properly. First we need to visit our blog:
cy.visit(&amp;lsquo;https://thebugger.io/&#39;);
Then, in order to check if github link is working, we need to click it and see if the outcome of this action is correct.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cypress - advantages and disadvantages</title>
      <link>https://jjaworski93.github.io/post/post6/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jjaworski93.github.io/post/post6/</guid>
      <description>To convince anyone how beneficial automated software testing is, is not needed. Automated software testing is much faster than manual testing and what is most important - it is repeatable. We need to rememberr however, that automated testing should be a great supplement and support for manual testing - not a replacement. The test script works only as it was programmed and does a great job. However, nothing can replace the skilled eye of an experienced tester.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>JavaScriptExecutor in Selenium - introduction</title>
      <link>https://jjaworski93.github.io/post/post5/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jjaworski93.github.io/post/post5/</guid>
      <description>It turns that Crayfish might be much smarter than we have ever imagined. So clever, they can grow new brain cells from their own blood. However, this article will be about JavascriptExecutor in Selenium. You may come across situations where Selenium WebDriver alone will not be able to perform certain operations or interact with some web elements, like unexpected pop-ups. In that case, JavascriptExecutor comes in handy. Let’s have a closer look on that topic.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Waits in Selenium - quick overview</title>
      <link>https://jjaworski93.github.io/post/post4/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jjaworski93.github.io/post/post4/</guid>
      <description>Let&amp;rsquo;s have a closer look at Implicit and Explicit Wait in Selenium. The wait commands play essential role when it comes to automated testing. They help to avoid issues that may occur due to variation in time lag. When the webpage loads in the browser, its elements may load at different time intervals. This may lead to the situation in which our automated test will look for an element that is not yet loaded and an exception will be thrown - ElementNotVisibleException.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The differences between TDD and BDD</title>
      <link>https://jjaworski93.github.io/post/post3/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jjaworski93.github.io/post/post3/</guid>
      <description>In this blog post we are going to discover the main differences between two testing-related concepts - Test Driven Development and Behavior Driven Development. TDD and BDD are two widely used software development techniques in which automated testing plays a central role. Today we are going to explore the differences.
Let&amp;rsquo;s start with Test Driven Development. Typically, in this technique, we write tests for a certain piece of functionality before writing the production code.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Selenium - advantages and disadvantages</title>
      <link>https://jjaworski93.github.io/post/post2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jjaworski93.github.io/post/post2/</guid>
      <description>Creating and adding your project to GitHub can let you build your portfolio, share your work and collaborate with others. Let&amp;rsquo;s start! In case you don&amp;rsquo;t have Git installed yet, check this article on how to set it up.
If you already have Git installed, create a new repository on GitHub, open Terminal and navigate into the directory where your source code (project) is located and initialize the local directory as a Git repository using:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to add a project to GitHub using command line</title>
      <link>https://jjaworski93.github.io/post/post1/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jjaworski93.github.io/post/post1/</guid>
      <description>Creating and adding your project to GitHub can let you build your portfolio, share your work and collaborate with others. Let&amp;rsquo;s start! In case you don&amp;rsquo;t have Git installed yet, check this article on how to set it up.
If you already have Git installed, create a new repository on GitHub, open Terminal and navigate into the directory where your source code (project) is located and initialize the local directory as a Git repository using:</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
